So a database, will usually have several tables in it.
一个数据库通常包含几个表
Here's how we might start for our image voting app.
我们或许可以这样开始设计图片投票应用
The first table represents pictures that people have uploaded of animals.
第一个表代表人们已经上传的动物图片
The second represents people's votes.
第二个代表人们的投票
Fluffy, Monster, and
Fluffy、Monster 和
George are all animals, whose pictures someone has uploaded.
George 都是动物 一些人上传了它们的图片
Because, we might have two animals with the same name.
由于我们可能遇到两个动物名字一样的情况
We give each one a numeric id here.
所以在这里 我们给每个动物一个数字 ID
The pictures tables says that Fluffy has id 1.
图片表中指定了 Fluffy 的 ID 是 1
Monster has id 2.
Monster 的 ID 是 2
George has id 3.
George 的 ID 是 3
And so on.
依此类推
The votes table says, which images have been displayed together for
投票表指定了投票时哪些图片一起显示
voting, and which one the user picked as the cutest.
哪些图片是用户选出的它们认为最可爱的
Here, the app displayed monster, ID 2, and George, ID 3,
这里 应用程序显示 monster 的 ID 是 2 George 的 ID 是 3
and the user voted for George.
用户投票给 George
2 and 3 were matched up, and 3 was the winner.
2和3相比 3胜出
Note that in the votes table,
注意 在投票表格中
the columns are called left, right, and winner.
虽然列被命名为 left、Right 和 winner
But they match up, to the column called id in the pictures table.
但它们与图片表格中被命名为 ID 的列匹配
You can read every row as a sentence.
你可以将每行作为一个句子
In the pictures table, the sentences say Fluffy has id number 1, and
在图片表格中 这些句子说的是 Fluffy 的 ID 号为 1
the filename fluffsocute.jpg, Monster has id number 2,
文件名为 fluffsocute.jpg Monster 的 ID 号为 2
and filename monstie-basket.png and so forth.
文件名为 monstie-basket.png 诸如此类
In the votes table, the sentences are picture 2 and
在投票表格中 这些句子表示 图片2
picture 3, were displayed and the user voted for picture 3.
和图片3一起显示 用户投票给图片3
Picture 1 and picture 3 were displayed, and
图片1和图片3一起显示
the user voted for picture 1 and so on.
用户投票给图片1 等等
So this 3 and this 3, refer to the same thing, a cute critter with id number 3.
因此 这个3和这个3指的是同一样东西 一个 ID 号为3的可爱动物
But they're in different tables, and the columns have different names,
但它们在不同的表格 而且列的名称不同
because they play different roles in different sentences.
因为它们在不同的句子中发挥不同的作用
Over here we're saying, which picture has which id?
这里 我们要表达的是 哪个图片对应哪个 ID？
And over here we're saying, which ones have been displayed together, and
这里 我们要表达的是 哪几张图片一起显示
who got the vote?
谁得到了选票？
So this is the kind of sentence that this table actually represents.
因此 这是这个表所表达的意思
If you wanted to come up with sentences like Monster was shown to Fluffy, and
如果对于这一行 你想说的是 Monster 和 Fluffy 一起显示
Fluffy got the vote instead of 2 was shown with 1,
Fluffy 得到选票 而不是2与1一起显示
and 1 got the vote for this row here.
1得到选票
We would have to connect rows from this table, with rows from that table.
我们就需要把这个表格的行与那个表格的行连接在一起
That's something we can do with a database query as well.
这也是我们能用数据库查询进行的一项操作
Queries that do this are called joins, and
执行这一操作的查询语句是 join
we'll be seeing a lot of them later on in the course.
我们会在后面的课程中看到很多相关的例子
For now, just remember that a value with the same meaning,
眼下 只要记住含义相同的值
can occur in different tables and have different column names, and
可以以不同的列名出现在不同表格中
that we can derive new tables by linking up existing tables using joins.
我们可以使用 join 把现有的表连接在一起 得到新的表